Project Files, 1986-2003
Smithsonian Institution Archives
Project Files
1986-2003
Smithsonian Institution Archives, Washington, D.C., osiaref@si.edu
National Museum of the American Indian, Office of Public Affairs
SI Records
8 cu. ft. (8 record storage boxes)
Accession 04-170
Descriptive Entry
This accession consists of project files, including correspondence with sponsors and media, memoranda, press releases, newspaper clippings, project proposals, legislative information, photographs, event files, advertisements, publicity reports and planning files. Particularly well documented is the transfer of the Museum of the American Indian to the Smithsonian and the opening of the George Gustav Heye Center (GGHC).
Index Terms
This collection is indexed under the following access terms. These are links to collections with related topics, persons or places.
Name
Heye, George G. (George Gustav), 1874-1957; Museum of the American Indian, Heye Foundation.
Subject
Indians of North America
Physical Characteristics of Materials in the Collection
Manuscripts; Clippings; Brochures; Newsletters; Black-and-white photographs; Color photographs; Color transparencies; Sound recordings
- Box 1
  - Publicity Plan - GGHC, 1994 (Box 1 of 8)
  - Clippings for GGHC Opening (Box 1 of 8)
  - Executive Summary - GGHC Exhibitions and Programs, 1994 (Box 1 of 8)
  - Linda's Notes re: GGHC Opening (Box 1 of 8)
  - Heye Center Opening - Evaluations/Critiques (Box 1 of 8)
  - Tribes in Heye Center Opening Exhibits (Box 1 of 8)
  - W. Richard West (WRW) Biography (Box 1 of 8)
  - WRW Photographs, 1997 (2 folders) (Box 1 of 8)
  - WRW Media Training (Box 1 of 8)
  - WRW Article Reprints and Statement on Appointment (Box 1 of 8)
  - WRW Speaking Engagements (Box 1 of 8)
  - WRW Europe Trip, October 1990 (Box 1 of 8)
  - WRW - Sioux Falls, September 27, 1990 (Box 1 of 8)
  - Press Kits, 1990 (Box 1 of 8)
  - SMG Biographies: George Horse Capture (Box 1 of 8)
  - Bernstein, Bruce (Box 1 of 8)
  - Evelyn, Doug (Box 1 of 8)
  - Colonghi, John (Box 1 of 8)
  - Recruitment for OPA (Office of Public Affairs) Jobs
  - Rick Hill (Box 1 of 8)
  - Karen Fort (Box 1 of 8)
  - Alica Maria Gonzalez (Box 1 of 8)
  - John Haworth (Box 1 of 8)
  - Charlotte Heth (Box 1 of 8)
  - David Warren (Box 1 of 8)
  - Staff Resumes (Box 1 of 8)
  - Speechwriters: Newsletter (Box 1 of 8)
  - WRW Comments from Tribal Leaders re: Appointment (Box 1 of 8)
  - Images of Indian Culture, September 18, 1990 (Box 1 of 8)
  - WRW Speeches, 1990-1991 (Box 1 of 8)
  - Speech: WRW "1992 Speech" (Box 1 of 8)
  - WBEZ Interview with WRW (Box 1 of 8)
  - USA Today Article (Box 1 of 8)
  - Biographical Information on WRW (Box 1 of 8)
  - PR Samples of Brochures (2 folders) (Box 1 of 8)
  - Sakakawea Statue Dedication, 2003 (Box 1 of 8)
  - Special Committee (Box 1 of 8)
  - Press Queries re: Repatriation (Box 1 of 8)
  - Repatriation Policy, March 5, 1991 (Box 1 of 8)
  - Repatriation Project Charter, November 3, 1993 (Box 1 of 8)
  - Repatriation: Kwakiutl, September 11, 1992 (Box 1 of 8)
- Box 2
  - Repatriation: Jemez Pueblo, October 27, 1993 (Box 2 of 8)
  - Repatriation: Northern Cheyenne, October 9, 1993 (National Museum of Natural History - NMNH) (Box 2 of 8)
  - Repatriation: Southern Cheyenne, July 1, 1993 (Box 2 of 8)
  - Repatriation Issues (Box 2 of 8)
  - National Museum of the American Indian (NMAI) Old Press Releases, 1989-1991 (Box 2 of 8)
  - Campbell Testimony, March 9, 1989 (Box 2 of 8)
  - Adams Testimony, July 9, 1989 (Box 2 of 8)
  - Court Order of Transferring Collection (Box 2 of 8)
  - History of Smithsonian Involvement with Heye Foundation (Box 2 of 8)
  - NMAI Film/Video Festival (Box 2 of 8)
  - Spanish Pathways Release (Box 2 of 8)
  - Spanish Language Brochure (Box 2 of 8)
  - Tribal Colleges (Box 2 of 8)
  - People Magazine Press Call (Box 2 of 8)
  - MAI Background (Box 2 of 8)
  - NMAI Background (Box 2 of 8)
  - "This Path We Travel: Celebrations" (Box 2 of 8)
  - Press Kit Contents (Box 2 of 8)
  - Turner Broadcasting System: The Native Americans (Box 2 of 8)
  - Tribal Leaders Directory from BIA (Box 2 of 8)
  - Indian Identity Policy, October 8, 1993 (Board of Trustees) (Box 2 of 8)
  - Media/Press Contacts with Interest in NMAI (Box 2 of 8)
  - "All Roads Are Good" (Box 2 of 8)
  - "All Roads Are Good" Object List (Box 2 of 8)
  - NMAI Board of Trustees, 1996-1997 (3 folders) (Box 2 of 8)
  - Board of Trustees Handbook (Box 2 of 8)
  - Board of Trustees and Committees (Box 2 of 8)
  - GGHC Board of Directors (Box 2 of 8)
  - Custom House History and Data (Box 2 of 8)
  - "Orientation" Project - GGHC, 1994 (Box 2 of 8)
  - GGHC Historic Preservation Guidelines (Box 2 of 8)
  - Speech: WRW's 1994 Basic GGCH Opening (Box 2 of 8)
  - Special Committee (Box 2 of 8)
  - Repatriation Issues and Trip Reports
  - Preservation or Reburial? Background Manuscript (Box 2 of 8)
  - Repatriation: King, Marcia/Seattle Times (Box 2 of 8)
  - Repatriation Update (Box 2 of 8)
  - Repatriation of Native American Cultural Patrimony - Pending (Box 2 of 8)
  - Repatriation Issues (Box 2 of 8)
  - Repatriation: Coroma, Aymara, Bolivia (Box 2 of 8)
  - NMAI/Heye Foundation - Human Remains (Box 2 of 8)
  - Repatriation: McCarthy, Robert - Dimensions Magazine (Box 2 of 8)
  - Repatriation of Skeletal Remains from Prince William Sound, Alaska (Box 2 of 8)
- Box 3
  - Repatriation (Box 3 of 8)
  - Repatriation Information, Policy, etc. (Box 3 of 8)
  - Repatriation Transcripts - NPR, July 1990 (Box 3 of 8)
  - Policy accommodations on Repatriation of Skeletal Remains (Box 3 of 8)
  - Panel Report on Indian Remains and Funerary Objects (Box 3 of 8)
  - June 1996 - Present (Box 3 of 8)
  - NMAI - Omaha Tribe Repatriation, Summer 1991 (Box 3 of 8)
  - Letters from Public on Indian Remains (Box 3 of 8)
  - Letters to Respond To (Box 3 of 8)
  - Sacredness (Box 3 of 8)
  - Sacred Objects Bibliography (Box 3 of 8)
  - Field Museum Policy (Box 3 of 8)
  - Repatriation Legislation (Box 3 of 8)
  - Buffalo Robe Return (Box 3 of 8)
  - NMAI Indian Repatriation Policy Controversy (Box 3 of 8)
  - Other Documentation - March 5 Press Conference (Box 3 of 8)
  - NMAI Repatriation Policy (Box 3 of 8)
  - News Clippings from March 5 Press Conference, 1991 (Box 3 of 8)
  - Repatriation Legislation (Box 3 of 8)
  - September 12, 1989 - Press Conference (Box 3 of 8)
  - Summary of September 12 News Conference (Box 3 of 8)
  - Articles from September 12 Press Conference (Box 3 of 8)
  - September 12 Press Conference (Box 3 of 8)
  - Indian Clippings (Box 3 of 8)
  - Indian Articles - Controversies (Box 3 of 8)
  - MAI Chronology (Box 3 of 8)
  - NMAI Chronology (Box 3 of 8)
  - Background Fact Sheet (Box 3 of 8)
  - Ad Samples (Box 3 of 8)
  - GGHC Prospectus (Box 3 of 8)
  - Aspen Celebration Week for the Native American (Box 3 of 8)
  - NMAI PR Samples, Press Kit Samples, and Reprints (2 folders) (Box 3 of 8)
- Box 4
  - NMAI PR Samples, Press Kit Samples, and Reprints (2 folders) (Box 4 of 8)
  - NMAI Custom House Opening (Box 4 of 8)
  - Native Peoples Magazine (Box 4 of 8)
  - Smithsonian Repatriation Policy (Box 4 of 8)
  - NMAI - April 11, 1988 Amendment (Box 4 of 8)
  - Petition to Supreme Court, NY, from MAI, 1986 (Box 4 of 8)
  - S.1722 - Inouye Bill (Box 4 of 8)
  - Important Notes - Press Calls (Box 4 of 8)
  - Correspondence with Suzan Harjo (Box 4 of 8)
  - NMAI Budget Figures (Box 4 of 8)
  - Writers Dialogue - NMAI (Box 4 of 8)
  - Exhibitions (Box 4 of 8)
  - NMAI Task Groups (Box 4 of 8)
  - Names of Smithsonian Staffers - Indians (Box 4 of 8)
  - Indian Articles (Box 4 of 8)
  - NCAI - Information (Box 4 of 8)
  - Adams Quote - NMAI, November 13, 1989 (Box 4 of 8)
  - Huntington Library (Box 4 of 8)
  - Oklahoma Regional Meeting, May 30-June 1, 1990 (Box 4 of 8)
  - Oklahoma, July 11-13, 1990 (Box 4 of 8)
  - NMAI - Latin American Outreach (Box 4 of 8)
  - Trips Abroad - NMAI (Box 4 of 8)
  - NMAI Cooperation with Oklahoma (Box 4 of 8)
  - Native American Committee (Box 4 of 8)
  - Interior Department (Box 4 of 8)
  - American Indian Heritage Month (Box 4 of 8)
  - American Indian Internships - Outreach Proposal (Box 4 of 8)
  - Trip Report (Box 4 of 8)
  - National Indian Education Association (Box 4 of 8)
  - Kidwell, Clara Sue - NMAI Assistant Director for Cultural Resources (Box 4 of 8)
  - NPC Speech by Rick West (Box 4 of 8)
  - Custom House Opening Planning Meetings (Box 4 of 8)
  - Harpers Article - Skeletal Remains, 1988 (Box 4 of 8)
  - Reception at Wheelwright, August 19, 1989 (Box 4 of 8)
  - July 29, 1988 Testimony - Melcher Bill, Skeletal Remains (Box 4 of 8)
  - November 12, 1987 - Adams, S.1722, S.1723 (Box 4 of 8)
  - Hearing, November 12, 1987 - Notes, November 18 (Box 4 of 8)
  - February 20, 1987 - Adams, S.187 Native American Cultural Preservation Act (Box 4 of 8)
  - Affiliation Agreement - MAI/Smithsonian (Box 4 of 8)
  - Revised NMAI Legislation, September 20, 1988 (Box 4 of 8)
  - Draft Legislation (Box 4 of 8)
  - Model - MAI Letter to Moynihan (Box 4 of 8)
  - January 30, 1989 Resolution - Board of Regents (Box 4 of 8)
  - January 25 MOU with MAI (Box 4 of 8)
  - Regional Indian Meetings (Box 4 of 8)
  - NMAI Bill Signing, November 1989 (Box 4 of 8)
  - NMAI Blessing Ceremony (Box 4 of 8)
  - Heye Transfer to Smithsonian - News Release, June 21, 1990 (Box 4 of 8)
  - November 19, 1990 - NYC Meeting/NMAI Custom House (Box 4 of 8)
  - Custom House Renovation Plan - NMAI (Box 4 of 8)
- Box 5
  - NMAI Convener's and Staff Meeting, August 7, 1990 (Box 5 of 8)
  - NMAI - Planning Documents (Square Footage, Operating Costs, etc.) (Box 5 of 8)
  - Smithsonian/MAI Final Agreement - Basis for Release, 1989 (Box 5 of 8)
  - Questions and Answers (Box 5 of 8)
  - Logistics - Press Conference (Box 5 of 8)
  - Photos from May 8 (Box 5 of 8)
  - NMAI - Search Committee (Box 5 of 8)
  - Objections to S.978 (Box 5 of 8)
  - Background - S.978 (Box 5 of 8)
  - Testimony, May 12, 1989 - Secretary Adams on NMAI (S.978) (Box 5 of 8)
  - May 12 Hearing - NMAI (Box 5 of 8)
  - NMAI Testimony, July 20, 1989 (Box 5 of 8)
  - Mall Museum Clippings (Box 5 of 8)
  - Mall Museum - Negative Press (Box 5 of 8)
  - Native Photo Images (Box 5 of 8)
  - Native Statistics (Box 5 of 8)
  - NCO Fact Sheet (Box 5 of 8)
  - Press Releases - Background and Outdated Releases (Box 5 of 8)
  - Press Releases, 1992-1994 (Box 5 of 8)
  - Press Releases, 1995-1996 (Box 5 of 8)
  - Press Releases, 1997 (Box 5 of 8)
  - Press Releases, 1999 (Box 5 of 8)
  - Conexus Press Releases (Box 5 of 8)
  - NCO Staff Press Releases (Box 5 of 8)
  - Gala Fact Sheet (Box 5 of 8)
  - Fact Sheets (Box 5 of 8)
  - Advance Exhibition Schedules (Box 5 of 8)
  - WRW Biography, 1998 (Box 5 of 8)
  - WRW Biography (Short Version) (Box 5 of 8)
  - Mall Backgrounder, 1997 (Box 5 of 8)
  - Board of Trustees, June 1997 (Box 5 of 8)
  - Heye Biography Press Releases (Box 5 of 8)
  - History of Events Press Releases (Box 5 of 8)
  - NMAI Now Open in NYC (Box 5 of 8)
  - Caring for American Indian Cultural Materials, 1996 (Box 5 of 8)
- Box 6
  - Vision Session, February 1995 (Box 6 of 8)
  - Mall Photos (Box 6 of 8)
  - Mall Museum Images (Box 6 of 8)
  - Original Images (Box 6 of 8)
  - Correspondence on Mall Images (Box 6 of 8)
  - Planning (2 folders) (Box 6 of 8)
  - Commission of Fine Arts (CFA) (Box 6 of 8)
  - CFA Press Materials - Originals (Box 6 of 8)
  - CFA Press Materials - Biographies (Box 6 of 8)
  - CFA Press Materials - Spanish Language Releases (Box 6 of 8)
  - CFA Hearing, May 16, 1996 (Box 6 of 8)
  - CFA Hearing - Biographies (Box 6 of 8)
  - CFA Hearing - Releases (Box 6 of 8)
  - CFA Hearing (Box 6 of 8)
  - Mail List (Box 6 of 8)
  - CFA Approval Mailing (Box 6 of 8)
  - CFA (Box 6 of 8)
  - Smithsonian 150th (Box 6 of 8)
  - John Colonghi Private Files (Box 6 of 8)
  - Smithsonian 150th Press Releases and Photos (Box 6 of 8)
  - NMAI 150th Plans (Box 6 of 8)
  - Photos and Slides - 150th (Box 6 of 8)
  - Collection Lists (Box 6 of 8)
  - CRC Response for NMAI Editorial Board (Box 6 of 8)
  - NMAI on the Mall - ODC Project #922307 (Box 6 of 8)
  - Letterhead for Press Materials (Box 6 of 8)
  - IFC (Box 6 of 8)
  - 1996-1997 NCO Files (Box 6 of 8)
  - Membership, 1997 (Box 6 of 8)
- Box 7
  - Campaign Mail Solicitations and Ephemera (Box 7 of 8)
  - Membership Drive (Box 7 of 8)
  - Dances with Wolves (Box 7 of 8)
  - NMAI Aspen Trip (Box 7 of 8)
  - NMAI Brainstorming Meeting, January 17, 1991 (Box 7 of 8)
  - NMAI, June 14, 1990 (Box 7 of 8)
  - MAI Memo to Burnette on Public Relations/Development (Box 7 of 8)
  - February 26, 1990 Meeting on NMAI Fundraising (Box 7 of 8)
  - NMAI Course Related Marketing (Box 7 of 8)
  - NMAI Fundraising, January 7, 1991 (Box 7 of 8)
  - Campaign Team: NMAI (Box 7 of 8)
  - Campaign: NMAI Newsletter (Box 7 of 8)
  - Press Correspondence (Box 7 of 8)
  - Video Shoots and Photos (includes 1/4" audiotape) (Box 7 of 8)
  - Clippings Report File - NMAI Miscellaneous, 1994 and 1989 re: Repatriation (Box 7 of 8)
  - Indian Publicity Report, May 1991 (Box 7 of 8)
  - Indian Publicity Report, October 1993 (Box 7 of 8)
  - Indian Publicity Report, March 1993 (Box 7 of 8)
  - Indian Publicity Report, December 1990 (Box 7 of 8)
  - Indian Publicity Report, April 1990 (Box 7 of 8)
  - Indian Publicity Report, May 1991 (Box 7 of 8)
  - Indian Publicity Report, April 1992 (Box 7 of 8)
  - Indian Publicity Report, 1988-1996 (2 folders) (Box 7 of 8)
  - Major Appointments Releases (Box 7 of 8)
- Box 8
  - Clippings, 1989 (2 folders) (Box 8 of 8)
  - Articles on Native American Issues - Scholarly (Box 8 of 8)
  - News Articles - Skeletal Remains (Box 8 of 8)
  - News Articles (Box 8 of 8)
  - Media/Publicity Reports, 1992-1993 (Box 8 of 8)
  - 100 Questions/500 Nations Brochure (Box 8 of 8)
  - Collection Images (Box 8 of 8)
  - Articles (Box 8 of 8)
  - Paid Advertising (Box 8 of 8)
  - Review of Building (Box 8 of 8)
  - Native American Images (Box 8 of 8)
  - Runner (Box 8 of 8)